Name:

**WARREN HAWKER** 

Address Mobile: 07868 524928: Basement flat, 1a St Anne's Crescent, Lewes, East Sussex, BN7 1SB

**Email Address** 

hawker.warren@gmail.com

## **PROFILE**

Before I became a lifeguard and swimming teacher I was a highly qualified and experienced scuba diving instructor, with eight years experience in the leisure industry, including as an assistant dive centre manager. I also have four years experience in the retail and catering sectors. As my qualifications show, I am committed to the highest standards of professionalism, technical excellence, and health and safety. I have won two special commendations for customer care, both as a diving instructor and as a retail sales assistant. After 5 years of scuba diving I decided to take my skills into the world of teaching aquatics, which I have done for the past 5 years. During that time I have expanded my skills and knowledge to include Springboard diving, First Aid and most recently NPLQ training.

I am loyal and hardworking, and devote myself wholeheartedly to the company I represent. I get on very well with work colleagues, and always regard the customer as my first priority. I am a highly motivated, articulate and people-focussed individual, who always seeks better ways of doing things for the good of the business and of the customer. I have a high level of written English and computer skills.

## **KEY SKILLS**

- Ability to communicate quickly and effectively with learners in a training situation, both theoretically and practically
- Proven ability to instruct, examine and pass learners on a given course
- Ability to assess needs and tailor learning accordingly in order to achieve successful outcomes for learners
- Able to inspire confidence in others
- Communicates enthusiasm to others in a leisure environment
- Very good planning and organisational abilities
- Good time management and efficiency
- Excellent customer service skills
- Highly developed written communication skills
- Methodical with a high attention to detail
- Adheres to high health and safety standards
- Ability to work as a trustworthy part of a team as well as independently
- Motivated to develop and learn as an individual
- Computer literate to a high standard in a wide range of applications

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

October 2016 – October 2018 Education Volunteer

Raystede Centre for Animal Welfare

# **Key Responsibilities**

Assist the Education Officers with education-based activities

Help manage and coordinate groups of children who visit the centre

Give advice to customers regarding adopting and caring for domestic animals

Inform the public about animal welfare issues

October 2017 – Present  Key Responsibilities    October 2016 – November 20  Key Responsibilities	Swim Teacher and Casual Lifeguard  Teach group lessons across a wide range of Assess new students and assign them to the Keep paperwork for all my classes organised Coordinate with the other swim teachers regular Casual Leisure Attendant/Swim teacher  Ensure the safety and comfort of the centre Set up various sports equipment	e appropriate class d and up to date larding schemes of work  Lewes Leisure Centre
•	Keep the centre clean	- J 4 0 4 -
•	Teaching swimming lessons, both groups ar	nd 1-2-1s
October 2014 – Present  Key Responsibilities	Dive Coach/Secretary  Organise events and competitions for the clu Handle new membership enquiries Organise logistics for the club Assist other coaches and coach club membership	
April 2014 – October 2016 <b>Key Responsibilities</b>	Recreational Assistant/Swim teacher	Tunbridge Wells Sports Centre
• • • • • Key achievements •	Ensure the safety and comfort of the centre Set up various sports equipment Host children's parties Keep the centre clean Swimming teacher cover ASA Dive Coach level 1 ASA Dive Coach level 2	users
Oct 2011 – April 2014 Key Responsibilities	Freelance Scuba Diving Instructor	Brighton Diving Centre
• • • • • Key achievements	Teach students in both pool and open water Maintain health and safety standards Maintain and fix equipment Examine and certify new divers Monitor progress of trainees  New Qualification: PADI Master Scuba Dive	
Dec 2012 - Sen 2013		
Dec 2012 - Sep 2013	Kitchen Porter/Chef's assistant/Waiter  Diving Instructor and Assistant Manager	Chaula's Indian Restaurant, Lewes
April – Oct 2012  Key Responsibilities	Diving Instructor and Assistant Manager Divezone Diving Centre, Indonesia  Taught and examined students up to Dive Master level Managed customer lodgings Supervised diving staff Dealt with customer complaints, issues and requests Took payments from customers Organised day-to-day logistics	
•	Special certificate of commendation from PADI International for excellent customer service	

April – Oct 2011 Diving Instructor and Technician European Diving Centre, Fethiye, Turkey

Key achievements

Qualifications Gained: ASSET Equipment Technician

Oct 2010 – April 2011 Sales Assistant and Barista Steamer Trading Cookshop, Lewes

**Key achievements** 

Mystery Shopper award for customer service

March – Oct 2010 Diving Instructor and Sales Staff Sailing Club Divers (PADI 5\*resort), Vietnam

**Key Responsibilities** 

Taught dive courses to students up to Advanced Open Water level

Supervised local dive centre staff
 Took sole charge of shop while on duty
 Sold courses and promoted the company

Took care of VIP guests

Key achievements

Qualifications Gained
 Scuba Schools International (SSI) Instructor

### PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

April to Oct 2009 PADI Divemaster, PADI Open Water Dive Instructor (IDC)

December 2009 ASSET scuba diving equipment and Nitrox Technician and Cylinder tester

May 2010 Scuba Schools International (SSI) Instructor

October 2011 Powerboat Licence Level 2
June 2012 PADI Master Scuba Diver Trainer
January 2014 RLSS Pool Lifeguard (NPLQ)
Feburary 2014 ASA Swim Teacher level 1
March 2014 ASA Swim Teacher level 2
October 2014 ASA Dive Coach level 1
November 2015 ASA Dive Coach level 2

January 2019 RLSS Pool Lifeguard Training Assessor
June 2019 Level 3 Award in Education and Training

## **EDUCATION**

2007-2008 AS levels in Biology (C), Music (C), Computing (D) Sussex Downs College, Lewes, E Sussex

**Pre-Professional Music Diploma** 

2003-2007 GCSEs in Maths (A), History (A), ICT short course (A), Worth School, Turners Hill, W Sussex

Biology (B), Music (B), English Lit (B), English Lang (B),

Chemistry (B), French (B), Religious Studies (C)

## References

Betty Allen: <a href="mailto:betty.allen@talktalk.net">betty.allen@talktalk.net</a> – Senior diving coach and mentor, Tunbridge Wells diving club

Catherine Bray: Education@raystede.org - Education Officer, Raystede Centre for Animal Welfare

Jordan Brennan: <u>Jordan.brennan@freedom-leisure.co.uk</u> – Duty Manager, Uckfield Leisure Centre